Desmond, Thomas C.; Papers apap068
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Thomas C. Desmond Papers
1930-1972
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Desmond, Thomas C. (Thomas Charles), 1887-1972
apap068
1.8 cubic ft.
Press releases about his work and concerns as a New York State Senator, clippings about Senator Desmond and his wife, correspondence with Albert J. Abrams and reports and drafts on the Presidential primary system.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in December 1978.
Biographical Sketch
Thomas C. Desmond was born on September 15, 1887, in Middletown, Orange County, New York. He graduated in 1908 from Harvard University. Desmond was also the president and chief engineer for the Newburgh Shipyard, which built ships for the United States Navy. Among the vessels, he was in charge of the building was the U.S.S. Newburgh.
Desmond was the president of the New York Young Republicans club. He served as a member of the New York State Senate from 1931 through 1958 elected from Newburgh, New York. He was also the chairman of the Committee of Military Affairs in 1932 and the Committee on Public Printing in 1931. Desmond was married to Alice Curtis Desmond, an author, and photographer. They had no children.
He died on October 6, 1972, in Boston, Massachusetts.
Scope and Contents
Press releases about his work and concerns as a New York State Senator, 1946-60; clippings about Senator Desmond and his wife, Alice Curtis Desmond, author and photographer, 1956-72; correspondence with Albert J. Abrams, 1965, about naming a street in Newburgh after Desmond; and reports and drafts on the Presidential primary system, 1958-65.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following boxes:
Box 1 - Press Releases, 1954-1960
Box 2 - Press Releases, 1950-1953
Box 3 - Press Releases, 1946-1950, Lists, Undated, Automobile Insurance, Index to Contents of Books, 1930-1940, 1945, 1947, 1948
Box 4 - Scrapbooks, 1956-1960
Box 5 - Scrapbooks, 1960-1964
Box 6 - Scrapbooks, 1965-1972, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated, Miscellaneous Press Releases, Undated, Miscellaneous Presidential Nominating Procedures, Undated
Public Servants; Politics and Politicians; Older politicians; Politicians--New York (State); Newburgh (N.Y.); Press Releases; Lists (Document Genre); Indexes (Reference Sources); Scrapbooks; Correspondence; Desmond, Thomas Charles; Desmond, Alice Curtis; Abrams, Albert J.
- Box 1: Press Releases, 1954-1960; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Press Releases, 1959 March 19-1960 December 08 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1958 October 10-1958 December 05 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1958 May-1958 July (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1958 March 06-1958 March 30 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1958 February 02-1958 February 28 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1958 January 06-1958 January 30 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1957 November 08-1957 December 27 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, 1957 July 18-1957 October 07 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1957 March 01-1957 April 26 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1957 February 01-1957 February 28 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1957 January 07-1957 January 26 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1956 October 12-1956 December 28 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1956 May 02-1956 September 24 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1956 March 02-1956 April 30 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, 1956 February 04-1956 February 24 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 1956 January 09-1956 January 30 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1955 November 11-1955 December 29 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1955 October 17-1955 October 28 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 18)
  - Press Releases, 1955 April 28-1955 August 31 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, 1955 March 04-1955 March 25 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 20)
  - Press Releases, 1955 February 03-1955 February 27 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 21)
  - Press Releases, 1955 January 10-1955 January 23 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 22)
  - Press Releases, 1954 December 01-1954 December 15; Undated (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 23)
  - Press Releases, 1954 July 08-1954 November 27 (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 24)
  - Press Releases, 1954 March 10-1954 May 18; Undated (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 25)
  - Press Releases, 1954 February 01-1954 February 26; Undated (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 26)
  - Press Releases, 1954 January 05-1954 January 29; Undated (Box 1 (1-Box 1: Press Releases), Folder 27)
- Box 2: Press Releases, 1950-1953; 2
  - Press Releases, 1953 October 13-1953 December 30 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1953 May 07-1953 September 11 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1953 February 05-1953 April 27 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1953 January 03-1953 January 30; Undated (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1952 December 03-1952 December 29 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1952 September 07-1952 November 30 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1952 April 28-1952 August 15 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, 1952 February 01-1952 March 09 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1952 January 04-1952 January 31 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1951 November 04-1951 December 30 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1951 August 04-1951 October 22 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 11)
  - Releases, 1951 March 02-1951 July 19 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1951 February 01-1951 February 23 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1951 January 05-1951 January 26 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, 1950 December 07-1950 December 29 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 1950 August 13-1950 November 28 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1950 June 13-1950 July 28 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1950 May 11-1950 May 26 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 18)
  - Press Releases, 1950 March 03-1950 April 15; Undated (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, 1950 February 03-1950 February 24 (Box 1 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 20)
  - Press Releases, 1950 January 05-1950 January 27 (Box 2 (2-Box 2: Press Releases), Folder 21)
- Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance, Index to Contents of books, 1930-1940; 1945; 1946-1950; 3
  - Press Releases, 1949 December 02-1950 January 01 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1949 November 03-1949 November 30 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1949 August 25-1949 October 18 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1949 April 28-1949 July 18 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1949 March 03-1949 March 18 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1949 February 05-1949 February 27 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1949 January 03-1949 January 31 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, 1947 December 01-1947 December 29 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1947 September 23-1947 November 21 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1947 June 02-1947 August 22 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1947 March 10-1947 April 16 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1947 February 03-1947 February 28 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1947 January 03-1947 January 30 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1946 December 11-1946 December 29 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, 1946 November 01-1946 November 27 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 1946 August 01-1946 October 31 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1946 July 01-1946 July 26 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1946 March 07-1946 June 15 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 18)
  - Press Releases, 1946 February 04-1946 February 24 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, 1946 January 05-1946 January 27 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 20)
  - List, Rod and Gun Columnists, Undated (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 21)
  - List, Mailing List for real estate releases, Undated (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 22)
  - Automobile insurance, Undated (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 23)
  - Index to contents of books containing statements and addresses of Senator Thomas C. Desmond, 1930-1940; 1945; 1947; 1948 (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 24)
  - Chronological list of statements, addresses, etc. of Senator Thomas C. Desmond, Undated (Box 3 (3-Box 3: Press Releases, Lists, Automobile Insurance), Folder 25)
- Box 4: Scrapbooks, 1956-1960; 4
  - Scrapbook, 1956 February 15-1958 August 14 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1958 August 19-1958 November 01 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1958 November 02-1958 December 21 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1958 December 30-1959 April 02 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1959 April 04-1959 June 18 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1959 June 19-1959 September 24 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1959 October 01-1960 January 21 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1960 January 22-1960 June 01 (Box 4 (4-Box 4: Scrapbooks), Folder 8)
- Box 5: Scrapbooks, 1960-1964; 5
  - Scrapbook, 1960 June 02-1960 December 28 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1960 December 30-1961 October 29 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1961 November 01-1962 February 28 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1962 March 20-1962 October 12 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1962 October 01-1962 December 24 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1963 January 07-1963 March 12 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1963 March-1964 January (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1964 January 01-1964 February 27 (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1964 March-1964 June (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1964 July-1964 December (Box 5 (5-Box 5: Scrapbooks), Folder 10)
- Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Miscellaneous Press Releases, Miscellaneous Presidential Nominating Procedures, 1965-1972; Undated; 6
  - Scrapbook, 1965 January-1965 October (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1965 September-1965 December (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1966 January-1966 August (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1966 September-1967 October (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1967 November-1970 July (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1970 August-1972 August (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Press Releases, Undated (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Presidential Nominating Procedures, Undated (Box 6 (6-Box 6: Scrapbooks, Miscellaneous Correspondence, M), Folder 9)